<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Intelligence | Cognitive Psychometrics Lab</title>
    <link>https://hsulab.psy.ntu.edu.tw/tag/intelligence/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://hsulab.psy.ntu.edu.tw/tag/intelligence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Intelligence</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2021-2023 Cognitive Psychometrics Lab. All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://hsulab.psy.ntu.edu.tw/media/logo_hu39dac0accd2519207393463f587ca00e_161255_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url>
      <title>Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://hsulab.psy.ntu.edu.tw/tag/intelligence/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>補助人文及社會科學研究圖書計畫規劃主題：智力與性格差異 的理論與測量(從數理模型到神經運作與基因遺傳)</title>
      <link>https://hsulab.psy.ntu.edu.tw/project/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hsulab.psy.ntu.edu.tw/project/books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Psychology seeks to uncover universal principles (regularity) of human mind and also to care for individual (cultural) differences, and how to integrate both remains a challenge. The current plan serves as the foundation for the study of individual differences, which include mostly research themes in intelligence, personality, and their psychometrically based measures and scales. However, some of the scales involved are not without debate, and there is a need for clarification from the measurement-theory viewpoint. On the other hand, over the past 30 years the development of human genetics has provided (the study of) individual differences with new interpretations, and discussions from behavior genetics about intelligence and personality often touch the issue of gene-environment interactions. Further, advances in neuroimaging and electro-physiology have brought new perspectives to this field. Also, adaptive (and computerized) measurement tools for evaluation have been becoming the mainstream, and the development seems to toward the goal of individualized assessments. Accordingly, this project aims to increase the book collections/volumes of the NTU library from three perspectives. They are (I) well-known books concerning theories of intelligence and of personality, (II) books on measurement theory and on psychometrics concerning testing, and (III) books on genetics and on neural mechanism concerning individual differences. Under this project, we have purchased a total of 3380 items, including books, CDs, and dissertations. The full list of collections is attached at the end of this report. The NTU library also has established a website for book sorting and searching under this project. Please refer to &lt;a href=&#34;http://d8.lib.ntu.edu.tw/booklist/81273688880004786&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://d8.lib.ntu.edu.tw/booklist/81273688880004786&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;心理學研究企圖發掘心智活動的共通(規則)性並兼顧個人(文化)差異，而如何跨層次整合乃一大挑戰。本圖書計畫乃有關個別差異研究的奠基，尤其智力與性格的理論與量測向來是心理學研究中最能彰顯心智特質個別差異的兩大領域，且其所衍生的測驗工具或量尺十分倚賴心理計量的發展。然而量尺建構背後的科學哲學並非如物理科學般明確，其中隱晦之處仍有待數理心理學量測理論的釐清。另一方面，過去三十年來人類基因體研究的快速進展正為個別差異研究帶來新的詮釋，而行為遺傳學對性格、智力等心智特質的討論亦常論及基因遺傳與社會情境脈絡的相互影響。其中有關腦造影、電生理等記錄腦內活動訊號的測量，亦對個別差異研究方法帶來新的面向。特別地，近年來電腦化適性評量已蔚為主流，且有走向結合基因及腦造影技術以提供個人化評量的趨勢。據此，我們執行一以個別差異為主軸的三大方向購書計畫，分別是(一)智力及性格理論之經典文獻，(二)量測理論與測驗學說之發展，以及(三)個別差異的神經及遺傳基礎及其分析方法。在此計畫下我們共購入3380筆項目(包括書籍、光碟、 及數位論文)。本校圖書館並另闢專區供此計畫下所得之書目查詢，相關網站請見 &lt;a href=&#34;http://d8.lib.ntu.edu.tw/booklist/81273688880004786&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://d8.lib.ntu.edu.tw/booklist/81273688880004786&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
