<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tzu-Yao Lin | Cognitive Psychometrics Lab</title>
    <link>https://hsulab.github.io/author/tzu-yao-lin/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://hsulab.github.io/author/tzu-yao-lin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Tzu-Yao Lin</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2021-2023 Cognitive Psychometrics Lab. All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://hsulab.github.io/author/tzu-yao-lin/avatar_hu8733c7ed2b05ef4e9d2d9969239f9975_1765909_270x270_fill_q75_lanczos_center.jpg</url>
      <title>Tzu-Yao Lin</title>
      <link>https://hsulab.github.io/author/tzu-yao-lin/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>文化共識理論架構下的閾值理論延伸：排序型類別資料分析</title>
      <link>https://hsulab.github.io/project/ltcm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hsulab.github.io/project/ltcm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cultural consensus theory (CCT), developed by Batchelder and colleagues in the mid-1980s, is a cognitively-driven information-pooling approach to assess people&amp;rsquo;s consensus when the culturally correct answers are not known a priori, therefore helping measure the extent to which cultural knowledge or beliefs are shared. The CCT methodology originally aims at analyzing data consisting of binary (true/false or yes/no) responses to interview questions within a culturally-related context. Later work by Batchelder and colleagues extended CCT to account for the ordinal categorical data type (e.g., the Likert-type questionnaires). In this project we develop an alternative approach to CCT modeling for the ordinal categorical data type. Specifically, we incorporate a response-confidence embedded threshold theory into the CCT framework. We systematically evaluate the fit of the model by hierarchical Bayesian Markov chain Monte Carlo simulation, and the results will be discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;「文化共識理論」是一以認知模式為本之分析方法，由學者Batchelder及其同事於 1980年代發展出。此方法旨在分析群組人士在文化影響下對於某些知識或意見之共識，特別是當正確答案屬未知狀態。此方法最初發展僅限用於文化情境底下二分回答選項之資料，爾後Batchelder及其同事結合信號偵測理論及測驗理論的一些元素，將之延伸至可處理排序型類別資料(包括李克特量表)。本研究在「文化共識理論」架構下提出另一路徑，發展一結合反應信心於閾值理論的分析方法處理排序型類別資料。我們藉電腦模擬評估此法之可行性，特別是，我們採階層式貝氏統計法，透過馬可夫鏈蒙地卡羅法進行參數估計。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
