<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Law of Similarity | Cognitive Psychometrics Lab</title>
    <link>https://hsulab.psy.ntu.edu.tw/tag/law-of-similarity/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://hsulab.psy.ntu.edu.tw/tag/law-of-similarity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Law of Similarity</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2021-2023 Cognitive Psychometrics Lab. All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://hsulab.psy.ntu.edu.tw/media/logo_hu39dac0accd2519207393463f587ca00e_161255_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url>
      <title>Law of Similarity</title>
      <link>https://hsulab.psy.ntu.edu.tw/tag/law-of-similarity/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>心理物理學相似律所含參數之函數性質於費區納表徵下之探究</title>
      <link>https://hsulab.psy.ntu.edu.tw/project/los2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hsulab.psy.ntu.edu.tw/project/los2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project concerns a theoretical study of psychophysics.
We investigate the properties of the law of similarity (on
the Weber sensitivities) within the Fechnerian framework.
Instead of assuming differentiability, we rely on regular
variation to characterize the parameters in the law of
similarity. We also link our results to those in Iverson
(2006).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;此計畫屬心理物理學之理論研究，我們探討在費區納表徵下，作用
於韋伯敏感度的「相似律」屬性。有別於之前做法，我們從數學「
規律變異」角度切入，探討此「相似律」所含參數的函數特徵。我
們並將本研究結果與 Iverson (2006) 研究結果作進一步對照。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>心理物理學相似律與仿射表徵互動之探究</title>
      <link>https://hsulab.psy.ntu.edu.tw/project/los/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hsulab.psy.ntu.edu.tw/project/los/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this project we use the Fechner method (of taking the limit of sequence of integrals of jnd’s) to construct the scales in a (weakly balanced) affine representation. We postulate a psychophysical law of similarity, and study its impact on the possible functional forms in the affine representation. Under this framework we further study the conditions under which affine representations are also Fechnerian, and link the results to the solutions in Iverson (2006) that was worked out within the Fechnerian framework. The work of this project has been summarized in a paper titled “Conditions under which affine representations are also Fechnerian under the power law of similarity on the Weber sensitivities” to be published in the Journal of Mathematical Psychology (see the attached file).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我們採用一藉區辨極限及差異閾積分建構心理物理量尺的「費區納法」，探究心理物理「仿射表徵」之量尺性質。我們假設一心理物理「相似律」，探討在此同質性假設下，仿射表徵的量尺函數形式。我們並探究在此框設下，仿射表徵可簡化為費區納表徵的條件，並討論其與Iverson (2006) 於費區納表徵下所得之結果的關聯。本研究成果已寫成論文 ”Conditions under which affine representations are also Fechnerian under the power law of similarity on the Weber sensitivities”，且即將發表於Journal of Mathematical Psychology期刊（見附文）。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
